Guide to the Salo W. Baron Papers, 1900-1980
Department of Special Collections
- Series 5. Manuscript Series, 86.5 linear (173 boxes)
  - Nationalism and Religion (Box 392, Folder 20)
  - A History of Jewish Cultural Reconstruction; Preface to Blumenkranz (Box 392, Folder 21)
  - Problems of Jewish Identity from a Historical Perspective (Box 393, Folder 1)
  - Letter to M. Wohlgelernter (Box 393, Folder 2)
  - Problems of Jewish Identity (Box 393, Folder 3)
  - Nationalism and Religion in the World Today; Lecture June 16, 1969, Vienna (Box 393, Folder 4)
  - Book Note For Jewish Social Studies (Box 393, Folder 5)
  - Foreword to ... (Box 393, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified mss. plus note (Changing Patterns of Anti-Semitism?) (Box 393, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Studies at Universities: an early project by S. W. Baron (Box 393, Folder 8)
  - Problems of Jewish Identity (Box 393, Folder 9)
  - Introduction to JSS (Box 393, Folder 10)
  - The Council of Trent and Rabbinic Literature (Box 393, Folder 11)
  - The Council of Trent and Rabbinic Literature (Box 393, Folder 11)
  - Introductory Remarks (Box 393, Folder 12)
  - Introductory Remarks (Box 393, Folder 12)
  - Reflections on Ancient and Medieval Jewish Demography (Box 393, Folder 13)
  - Reflections on Ancient and Medieval Jewish Demography (Box 393, Folder 13)
  - Economic History, Jewish; Enciclopaedia Judaica (Box 393, Folder 14)
  - Economic History, Jewish; Enciclopaedia Judaica (Box 393, Folder 14)
  - Changing Pattern of Anti-Semitism (Box 393, Folder 15)
  - Changing Pattern of Anti-Semitism (Box 393, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified mss. (Box 393, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified mss. (Box 393, Folder 16)
  - Introduction to Ancient and Medieval Jewish History (Box 393, Folder 17)
  - Introduction to Ancient and Medieval Jewish History (Box 393, Folder 17)
  - Changing Pattern of Anti-Semitism; a survey (Box 393, Folder 18)
  - Changing Pattern of Anti-Semitism; a survey (Box 393, Folder 18)
  - Ferdinand Lasalle zu seinem 100. Geburtstag (Box 393, Folder 19)
  - Foreword to Vera B. Morien's "Iranian Jewry's Hour..." (Box 394, Folder 1)
  - American Reform Judaism and Zionism (Box 394, Folder 2)
  - Population (Box 394, Folder 3)
  - International Commission for a Scientific and Cultural History of Mankind (Box 394, Folder 4)
  - A Diplomatic Episode in the Spanish-Portuguese ... (Box 394, Folder 5)
  - How S.A. Jewry Should Plan Its Future (Box 394, Folder 6)
  - Modern Capitalism and Jewish Fate; offprint (Box 394, Folder 7)
  - The Jewish State and the Jewish People (Box 394, Folder 8)
  - Article in Hebrew; offprint (Box 394, Folder 9)
  - American Jewish Communal Pioneering; offprint (Box 394, Folder 10)
  - Conference Theme; reprint from: Publication of the Amercian Jewish Historical Society, vol. XLVI, no. 3 (1957)(1957) (Box 394, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Social Studies ..., vol. III, no. 3 (1941); reprint(1941) (Box 394, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Social Studies, vol. XXIV (1962)(1962) (Box 394, Folder 13)
  - American Jewish Communal Pioneering, 2 off-prints (Box 394, Folder 14)
  - Contemporary Jewish Record; off-print (Box 394, Folder 15)
  - Two articles in Hebrew; off-prints (Box 394, Folder 16)
  - Moritz Steinschneider's Contribution to Jewish History; offprint (Box 394, Folder 17)
  - Medieval Heritage and Modern Realities ...; off-print (Box 394, Folder 18)
  - The Year in Retrospect; off-print (Box 394, Folder 19)
  - The Jewish Community ...; off-print (Box 394, Folder 20)
  - Review of S. Cohen, "Contemporary Jewry," galleys (Box 394, Folder 21)
  - Jewish Social Studies; Subject Index (Box 394, Folder 22)
  - Ghetto and Emancipation; Reprint (Box 394, Folder 23)
  - Freedom and Constraint ...; off-print (Box 394, Folder 24)
  - The Jewish Question ...; reprint (Box 394, Folder 25)
  - The Spiritual Reconstruction ...; reprint (Box 394, Folder 26)
  - To the Editors of the Jewish Quarterly Review; offprint (Box 394, Folder 27)
  - Abraham Benisch's Project ...; reprint (Box 394, Folder 28)
  - Emphases in Jewish History; reprint (Box 394, Folder 29)
  - Nationalismus und Religion ...; offprint (Box 394, Folder 30)
  - Review of R.A. Billington, "The Protestant Crusade...;" galleys (Box 394, Folder 31)
  - Review of W. Chomsky, "David Kimhi's Hebrew Grammar ...;" galleys (Box 394, Folder 32)
  - Review of S. Luzzatto`s "Discourse on the States...;" galleys (Box 394, Folder 33)
  - Review of P. Robertson, "Revolutions of 1848 ...;" galleys (Box 394, Folder 34)
  - Review of F. Gilbert, ed., "Hitler Directs His War;" galleys (Box 394, Folder 35)
  - Review of J. Klauzner, "A History of the Jewish Community in Wilno;" galleys (Box 395, Folder 1)
  - A Bibliography of S.W. Baron (1912-73); galleys(1912-73) (Box 395, Folder 2)
  - The Revolution of 1848 ... (Box 395, Folder 3)
  - A Bibliography of S.W. Baron (1912-73); galleys(1912-73) (Box 395, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography in Hebrew (Box 395, Folder 5)
  - Can American Jewry Be Culturally Creative? (Box 395, Folder 6)
  - Palestinian Messengers ...; off-print (Box 395, Folder 7)
  - The Revolution of 1848 ... (Box 395, Folder 8)
  - The Cultural Revolution of the Russian Jewry ...; off-print (Box 395, Folder 9)
  - A Bibliography of S.W. Baron (1912-73) off-print(1912-73) (Box 395, Folder 10)
  - A Tentative List of Jewish Periodicals in Axis-occupied countries; off-print (Box 395, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Social Studies; 25th Anniversary Issue; "Newer Emphasis in Jewish History;" off-print (Box 395, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Social Studies, vol. XXIII (1961); off-print(1961) (Box 395, Folder 13)
  - World Dimensions of Jewish History; off-print (Box 395, Folder 14)
  - Nationalismus und Religion ...; off-print (Box 395, Folder 15)
  - Review of N. Cohen's ...?; galleys (Box 395, Folder 16)
  - Jewish Interdependence and the Alliance; off-print (Box 395, Folder 17)
  - Article in Hebrew (Box 395, Folder 18)
  - Are the Jews still the People of the Book? off-print (Box 395, Folder 19)
  - The Emancipation Movement and the American Jewry (Box 395, Folder 20)
  - Maimonides Symposium (Box 395, Folder 21)
  - The Jewish Community; in: Encyclopaedia Britannica (Box 395, Folder 22)
  - Second and Third Commonwealth ...; off-print (Box 395, Folder 23)
  - Pharisees; in: Encyclopaedia Britannica (Box 395, Folder 24)
  - International Commission for a History ... (Box 395, Folder 25)
  - Jakob Shatzky 1893-1956 (Box 395, Folder 26)
  - Article in Hebrew (Box 395, Folder 27)
  - Jews in Palestine 1800-1882 (Box 395, Folder 28)
  - My American Publishers and I ... (Box 395, Folder 29)
  - Bibliography of S.W. Baron (1977-86)(1977-86) (Box 395, Folder 30)
  - Ancient and Medieval Studies ...; Introduction (Box 395, Folder 31)
  - Moses Ben Maimon ...; Introduction (Box 395, Folder 32)
  - Aspects of the Jewish Communal Crisis (Box 396, Folder 1)
  - Alfred Fischel, Protocolle (Box 396, Folder 2)
  - Oxford Papers, notes (Box 396, Folder 3)
  - Ethnic Minority Rights; mss. (Box 396, Folder 4)
  - Colenbrander, "Recherches sur l'etat ...;" excerpts (Box 396, Folder 5)
  - Summary: The Role of the Rabbi in Traditional Literature (Box 396, Folder 6)
  - The Jewish State and the Jewish People; 2 copies (Box 396, Folder 7)
  - Summary: "Plenitude of Apostolic Powers ..." (Box 396, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Interdependence and the Alliance (Box 396, Folder 9)
  - Who is a Jew?; 2 copies (Box 396, Folder 10)
  - Philip Friedman (Box 396, Folder 11)
  - The Jewish Commonwealth and the Dispersions ... (Box 396, Folder 12)
  - The Jewish Commonwealth and the Dispersions; Summary (Box 396, Folder 13)
  - Foreword to the 2nd ed. of Nationalism and Religion; 3 copies (Box 396, Folder 14)
  - Medieval Nationalism and Jewish Serfdom (2 copies) (Box 396, Folder 15)
  - Hebrew Mss. (Box 396, Folder 16)
  - Letter to Isaak Scheersohn ... (Box 396, Folder 17)
  - Foreword to... E. Rosenberg, America is Different... (1963) (Box 396, Folder 18)
  - Foreword to J. Agus, (1963) (Box 396, Folder 19)
  - History of Religion: Faith or History? (Box 396, Folder 20)
  - Reply to Resident Truman (Nov. 18, 1962) (Box 396, Folder 21)
  - Some Medieval Attitudes to the Muslim State (2 copies) (Box 396, Folder 22)
  - Foreword to the Kohut Foundation Catalog (Box 396, Folder 23)
  - Nationalismus und Religion in der Heutigen Welt (Box 396, Folder 24)
  - Review of: The Letters and Papers of Chaim Weizmann (Box 396, Folder 25)
  - Cecil Roth, Necrology to AHR, 1970 (3 copies) (Box 396, Folder 26)
  - Reflections on Ancient and Medieval Historical Demography (3 copies) (Box 396, Folder 27)
  - Judaims, History of; Encyclopaedia Britannica (Box 396, Folder 28)
  - Recording Communal Priorities (Box 396, Folder 29)
  - Judaism, History of; in: Encyclopaedia Britannica (Box 397, Folder 1)
  - Review of L. Stein, ed.; Letters and Papers of Chaim Weizmann, vol. I (Box 397, Folder 2)
  - Cultural Needs of the Jewish Community (Box 397, Folder 3)
  - The Revolution of 1848 and Jewish Scholarship; part II: Austria (Box 397, Folder 4)
  - A Diplomatic Episode in the Spanish-Portuguese Community of London (1941) (Box 397, Folder 5)
  - Israel; in: Encyclopaedia Americana (Box 397, Folder 6)
  - Judaism, Historical Monotheism; in: Encyclopaedia Americana (Box 397, Folder 7)
  - Some Palestine Impressions (Box 397, Folder 8)
  - The Year in Retrospect (Box 397, Folder 9)
  - Mss. in Hebrew (Box 397, Folder 10)
  - Misc. (Box 397, Folder 11)
  - The Historical Outlook of Maimonides (Box 397, Folder 12)
  - Foreword to R. Ainsztein's English translation of Ginsbert-Lewins' Kantonists (Box 397, Folder 13)
  - The Economic History of the Jews (Box 397, Folder 14)
  - Anti-Semitism; notes in Hebrew (Box 397, Folder 15)
  - Hommage a Maimonides (Box 397, Folder 16)
  - The Revolution of 1848 and Jewish Scholarship; academic paper, Dec. 26, 1948 (Box 397, Folder 17)
  - Letter to the Editor of AHR (Box 397, Folder 18)
  - The Revolution of 1848 and Jewish Scholarship, part I (Box 397, Folder 19)
  - Civilization on Trial; Arnola J. Toynbee; review of? (Box 397, Folder 20)
  - Various book reviews in Jewish Social Studies 1937-53; galleys (Box 397, Folder 21)
  - Biographical Sketch of S. W. Baron (Box 397, Folder 22)
  - Letter to the Editors of the Jewish Quarterly Review (Oct. 14, 1952) (Box 397, Folder 23)
  - Some Recent Literature on the History of the Jews... (1300-1800) (Box 397, Folder 24)
  - Some Recent Literature on the History of the Jews... (1300-1800) (Box 397, Folder 25)
  - Nationalism and Religion in the World of Today; First National Colloquium of the Greek Orthodox (Box 398, Folder 1)
  - Review by Gerson D. Cohen of Abraham Ibn David, The Book of Tradition (Box 398, Folder 2)
  - Keeper of the Law; Blurb for Eli Ginzberg`s volume on his father, Louis Ginzberg (Box 398, Folder 3)
  - Benediction at Inauguration of Dr. Robert D. Cross (Box 398, Folder 4)
  - Postcript to the Foreword of the Hebrw Edition to S. Rosenberg, America is Different (Box 398, Folder 5)
  - Newer Approaches to Jewish Emancipation (3 copies) (Box 398, Folder 6)
  - Review of Z. Szajkowsky, "Jews, Wars, and Communism;" (4 copies) (Box 398, Folder 7)
  - Foreword to Ph. Friedman (Box 398, Folder 8)
  - Preface to Schwarz-Löwinger Catalogue (Box 398, Folder 9)
  - Impact of Wars on Religion (Box 398, Folder 10)
  - Some of the Tercentenary's Historic Lessons (Box 398, Folder 11)
  - Jews in Palestine, 1800-1880 (Box 398, Folder 12)
  - Great Britain and Damascus Jewry; plus Foreign Office documents (Box 398, Folder 13)
  - Mss. in Hebrew (Box 398, Folder 14)
  - The Genes of Genius (Box 398, Folder 15)
  - Ethnic Minority Rights (Box 398, Folder 16)
  - Newer Approaches to Jewish Emancipation (3 copies) (Box 398, Folder 17)
  - Some Recent Literature...; notebooks and misc. (Box 398, Folder 18)
  - Draft to Roth (Box 398, Folder 19)
  - Jewish Survival -- Historic Challenge (Box 398, Folder 20)
  - Impact of War on Religion (Box 398, Folder 21)
  - Great Britain and Damascus Jewry in 1860-61 (Box 399, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Historiography 75 years after Graetz (Box 399, Folder 2)
  - Medieval Folklore and Jewish Fate (Box 399, Folder 3)
  - From Colonial Mansion to Skyscraper (Box 399, Folder 4)
  - Some Recent Literature on the History of the Jews (Box 399, Folder 5)
  - Maimonides, the leader and land-giver; unpublished (Box 399, Folder 6)
  - Zur Geschichte der Haskala in der Napoleonischen Zeit; unpublished (Box 399, Folder 7)
  - Moses Cohen Belinfante ...; unpublished (Box 399, Folder 8)
  - Moses Ben Maimon; unpublished (Box 399, Folder 9)
  - Maimonides' Theories of Government; unpublished (Box 399, Folder 10)
  - Women's Part in Shaping the Jewish Future; unpublished (Box 399, Folder 11)
  - Reply to Frank; unpublished (Box 399, Folder 12)
  - The World Status of the Hebrew University; unpublished (Box 399, Folder 13)
  - Some Recent Literature... (Box 399, Folder 14)
  - The Jewish Factor in Medieval Civilization ... (Box 399, Folder 15)
  - Review of D. Druck's "Yehuda Halevi ..." (Box 399, Folder 16)
  - Review of "The Jewish Historical Society of England, Transactions ..." (Box 399, Folder 17)
  - Review of C. Roth's "A History of the Jews in England" (Box 399, Folder 18)
  - Review of "The Jews in France" (Box 399, Folder 19)
  - Necrology of H. Bernstein (Box 399, Folder 20)
  - Review of G. Antonius, "The Arabic Awakening" (Box 399, Folder 21)
  - Review of "Gaster Anniversary Volume" (Box 399, Folder 22)
  - Review of "The Jewish Historical Society of England, Transactions ..." (Box 399, Folder 23)
  - Review of M Traub, "Die jüdische Auswanderung ..." (Box 399, Folder 24)
  - Review of E. Hoffmann, "Die Liebe zu Gott ..." (Box 399, Folder 25)
  - Review of M. Cohen, "Jacob Emden, a Man of Controversy" (Box 399, Folder 26)
  - Review of Dr. Marcus` Source Book (Box 399, Folder 27)
  - Review of Conference on the Occasion of the Abravanel Quingentary (Box 399, Folder 28)
  - Review of J. Bloch, "Early Hebrew Printing in Spain and Portugal" (Box 399, Folder 29)
  - Review of W. O. E. Oesterley, "Sacrifices in Ancient Israel" (Box 399, Folder 30)
  - Review of J. Parkes` "The Jew in the Medieval Community" (Box 399, Folder 31)
  - Review of C. Roth, "Magna Biblioteca ..." (Box 399, Folder 32)
  - Review of S. Freud's "Moses and Monotheism" (Box 399, Folder 33)
  - Reply to Dr. Zeitlin's review of "The Economic Views of Maimonides" (Box 399, Folder 34)
  - "In reply to Dr. Mortimer Cohen" (Box 399, Folder 35)
  - Review of "Judaism and Christianity ..." (Box 399, Folder 36)
  - Review of L. Finkelstein, "The Pharisees ..." (Box 399, Folder 37)
  - Review of "The vicissitudes of Asher Hallery ..." (Box 399, Folder 38)
  - Review of D. Sidersby, "Quelsques portraits ..." (Box 399, Folder 39)
  - Review of S. Mézan, "De Cabirol à Abravanel" (Box 399, Folder 40)
  - Review of M. Reifer, "Ausgewählte Schriften" (Box 399, Folder 41)
  - Review of "Judaism and Christianity" (Box 399, Folder 42)
  - Review of R. L. Rusk, "Letters to Emma Lazarus..." (Box 399, Folder 43)
  - Review of "Scritti in onore di Dante Lattes" (Box 399, Folder 44)
  - Review of ? (Box 399, Folder 45)
  - Review of J. Vogt, "Kaiser Julian ..." (Box 399, Folder 46)
  - Reviews of "Joseph Halévy's Journey in Yemen" (Box 399, Folder 47)
  - Reviews of A. Sacher, Sufferance is the Badge (Box 399, Folder 48)
  - Review of? (Box 399, Folder 49)
  - Review of B. M. Ediden, Rebuilding Palestine (Box 399, Folder 50)
  - Review of H. W. Robinson, "The History of Israel" (Box 399, Folder 51)
  - Review of H. W. Robinson, "The History of Israel" (Box 399, Folder 52)
  - Review of "The British Consulate in Jerusalem" (Box 399, Folder 53)
  - Review of "The Jewish Fate and Future" (Box 399, Folder 54)
  - Review of "An Introduction to Philo Judäus" (Box 399, Folder 55)
  - Review of "The World of Nations" (Box 399, Folder 56)
  - Review of "A History of the Jewish Community in Wilna" (Box 399, Folder 57)
  - Review of "The Cultural Approach to History" (Box 399, Folder 58)
  - Review of "Some Recollections of C. Goldsmid and Montefiore" (Box 399, Folder 59)
  - Necrology on David Yellin (Box 399, Folder 60)
  - Necrology on Herman Bernstein (Box 399, Folder 61)
  - Necrology on Zevi Diesendruck (Box 399, Folder 62)
  - In Historic Perspective. Teen-Team Interview for "Our Age" (1965) (Box 400, Folder 1)
  - John Calvin and the Jews (Box 400, Folder 2)
  - Review of J. Guttman's "Philosophy of Judaism" (Box 400, Folder 3)
  - The Future of American Jewry (Box 400, Folder 4)
  - Introduction to George Brandes' "Lord Beaconsfield" (Box 400, Folder 5)
  - Foreword to Mr. Wischnitzer's book (on Jewish Guilds?) (Box 400, Folder 6)
  - Article in Hebrew (Box 400, Folder 7)
  - Article in Hebrew (Box 400, Folder 8)
  - Ethnic Minority Rights (Box 400, Folder 9)
  - Publication in English and Hebrew (Tempel Solel Manuel Tancer) (Box 400, Folder 10)
  - On the Conference of Jewish Social Studies (Box 400, Folder 11)
  - Judaeo-Osmanica (Box 400, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Immigration and Communal Conflicts ... (Box 400, Folder 13)
  - Church and State Debates in the Jewish Community in 1848 (Box 400, Folder 14)
  - Hebrew mss. (Box 400, Folder 15)
  - Jewish Studies at Universities (Box 400, Folder 16)
  - Aspects of the Jewish Communal Crisis in 1848 (Box 400, Folder 17)
  - Maimonides; mss (Box 401, Folder 1)
  - Essay on Maimonides; 14 notebooks (Box 401, Folder 2)
  - The Economic View of Maimonides (Box 401, Folder 3)
  - The Economic View of Maimonides (Box 401, Folder 4)
  - The Economic View of Maimonides, notes (Box 401, Folder 5)
  - The Historical Outlook of Maimonides; off-print (Box 401, Folder 6)
  - The Historical Outlook of Maimonides; reprint (Box 401, Folder 7)
  - Italian Jewry in the period of the Renaissance; pp. 1-100 (Box 402, Folder 1)
  - Italian Jewry in the period of the Renaissance; pp. 101-200 (Box 402, Folder 2)
  - Italian Jewry in the period of the Renaissance; pp. 201- (Box 402, Folder 3)
  - Italian Jewry in the period of the Renaissance; handwritten notes (Box 402, Folder 4)
  - Excerpts from "Gli Ebrei nell'Italia Meridionale" (Box 402, Folder 5)
  - Palestine and Jerusalem (Box 402, Folder 6)
  - History: 2nd to 6th centuries; pp. 1-100 (Box 402, Folder 7)
  - History: 2nd to 6th centuries; pp. 101-200 (Box 402, Folder 8)
  - Bound Reprints of S. W. Baron's articles (1926-42); 46 articles; for titles, consult table of contents(1926-42) (Box 403, Folder 1)
  - Bound Reprints of S. W. Baron's articles (1923-42)(1923-42) (Box 404, Folder 1)
  - Bound Reprints of S. W. Baron's articles (1918-38); table of content(1918-38) (Box 405, Folder 1)
  - Queries in Retrospect; offprint (Box 406, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum for Testimony April 24, 1961April 24, 1961 (Box 406, Folder 2)
  - Holocaust Colloquium, Dropsie University, April 11, 1973April 11, 1973 (Box 406, Folder 3)
  - Draft of Testimony, April 1961April 1961 (Box 406, Folder 4)
  - Holocaust Colloquium, Dropsie University, April 11, 1973April 11, 1973 (Box 406, Folder 5)
  - Testimony for Eichmann-Trial; english summary and text in Hebrew (April 1961)(April 1961) (Box 406, Folder 6)
  - Address for the Salo and Jeanette Baron Prize in Jewish Studies (Box 407, Folder 1)
  - Challenges to Jewish Philanthropy; address at the Symposium of the Federation of Jewish (Box 407, Folder 2)
  - Action Through Knowledge; Summary; Address at the National Federation of Jewish Men's Clubs (1964)(1964) (Box 407, Folder 3)
  - Interview with S. W. Baron; transcript of tape (Box 407, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Learning and the present crisis (Box 407, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Communities; Lectures (1936)(1936) (Box 407, Folder 6)
  - History 174; Jews in America (Box 407, Folder 7)
  - History 114A; Lecture 1950 (Box 407, Folder 8)
  - History 173; American History (1948)(1948) (Box 407, Folder 9)
  - Introductory Remarks; Conference on Jewish Social Studies (1962)(1962) (Box 407, Folder 10)
  - Address at Graduation Exercises (Oct. 28, 1934); unpublished (Box 407, Folder 11)
  - Summary of address at the AHA (Dec. 1936)(Dec. 1936) (Box 407, Folder 12)
  - Lecture given at the Jewish Theological Seminar (Jan. 9, 1933)(Jan. 9, 1933) (Box 407, Folder 13)
  - The Jewish Heritage ...; Boston Lectures (Oct. 1945)(Oct. 1945) (Box 407, Folder 14)
  - International Aspects of the Jewish Problem (1947)(1947) (Box 407, Folder 15)
  - History 201; Philosophies of History (1947)(1947) (Box 407, Folder 16)
  - History 405; Religious Liberty: Areas of Investigation (1947)(1947) (Box 407, Folder 17)
  - Address to ? when ? (Box 407, Folder 18)
  - American Jewish Heritage; address to the "Society of the Judaeans;" Jan. 20, 1952Jan. 20, 1952 (Box 407, Folder 19)
  - Address to? (Box 407, Folder 20)
  - American Jewish History ...; AJHS (Feb. 19, 1949)(Feb. 19, 1949) (Box 407, Folder 21)
  - Liberalism and the Jew ...; Lecture given at the University of Illinois (Dec. 5, 1954)(Dec. 5, 1954) (Box 407, Folder 22)
  - Article in Hebrew (Box 408, Folder 1)
  - Mss. in Hebrew (Box 408, Folder 2)
  - Paper given at the Symposium "Israel and the Diaspora" (1978)(1978) (Box 408, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Semitism; article for Encyclopaedia (Box 408, Folder 4)
  - "This, Above Else" (Box 408, Folder 5)
  - Address to the Biennial Congress ... (March 13-16, 1958)(March 13-16, 1958) (Box 408, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Miss Lotta Levensohn to Mrs. Jacobs (April 21, 1942)(April 21, 1942) (Box 408, Folder 7)
  - Zur Geschichte der Englischen Judenpolitik (Box 408, Folder 8)
  - Short-story (?) by S. W. Baron; handwritten mss. (Box 408, Folder 9)
  - Die Judenfrage auf dem Wiener Kongress; S. W. Baron's dissertation (Box 408, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Contributions to Culture; Summary of address on American Jewry (Box 409, Folder 1)
  - History 173; Jews in America (1948-49); duplicate(1948-49) (Box 409, Folder 2)
  - History 173; Jews in America (1948-49)(1948-49) (Box 409, Folder 3)
  - History 201; Ancient and Medieval Philosophies (Oct. 7, 1948)(Oct. 7, 1948) (Box 409, Folder 4)
  - The World looks to America (III) (Box 409, Folder 5)
  - Final Stages of Jewish Emancipation (I) (Box 409, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Institute of Religion, Summer Institute Lectures, June 14-17, 1943June 14-17, 1943 (Box 409, Folder 7)
  - History 174 (Syllabus); History 201 (Dec. 9, 1948)(Dec. 9, 1948) (Box 409, Folder 8)
  - Seminar on Religion and Democracy (Nov. 1947); "Religious Liberty: Areas of Investigation"(Nov. 1947) (Box 409, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography of S. W. Baron (1912-1945)(1912-1945) (Box 409, Folder 10)
  - Syllabi and reading lists for exams (ca. 1950-60)(ca. 1950-60) (Box 409, Folder 11)
  - "The Jews in the era of the Reformation; "History G6571x; Syllabus (33 copies) (Box 409, Folder 12)
  - History 174; History A; various bibliographies (Box 409, Folder 13)
  - Conference on Anti-Semitism (Transcript of Tape); Conference on Jewish Social Studies, November 1961 (Box 410, Folder 1)
  - "Some Writers of Religious History;" History 201 (Dec. 9, 1948)(Dec. 9, 1948), ; syllabus (Box 410, Folder 2)
  - The Third Horcace M. Kallen Lecture (May 10, 1973)(May 10, 1973) (Box 410, Folder 3)
  - Intellectural Life/Weltanschauung/Middle Ages; Lectures (Box 410, Folder 4)
  - Jews in Medieval Europe, Lecture (Box 410, Folder 5)
  - History 137 (1938-39)(1938-39) (Box 410, Folder 6)
  - Population Problems of Modern Jewry; History 137 (1938)(1938) (Box 410, Folder 7)
  - Political History of the Jews in the 19th century (Box 410, Folder 8)
  - History A; bibliography (21 copies) (Box 410, Folder 9)
  - Syllabi (Box 410, Folder 10)
  - Convocation Miami Beach (Feb. 24, 1965)(Feb. 24, 1965) (Box 411, Folder 1)
  - Princeton Conference, Luncheon Address (March 21, 1976)(March 21, 1976) (Box 411, Folder 2)
  - Is America Ready For Minority Rights? part I; Hilldale Lecture (Nov. 3, 1983)(Nov. 3, 1983) (Box 411, Folder 3)